[Add appropriate subtitle text here]
Consider yourself dead.
You are here to prepare for the gap
between birth and death.
You have no identity.
On No Moon you will be reborn.
You do not need to speak.
Just nod or shake your head.
Is this your first time?
How did you know here?
I see.
They will show you to your tent.
Our last guest has arrived
so the boundary is now closed.
Today is the Full Moon.
None of you will leave until No Moon.
You want to remain unknown.
That's why you all wear masks and skirts.
You don't even want other people to know
your gender.
It's your own decision.
You are here to find out who you
really are.
You are all here to find out what you
would do if you were not known.
This only happens once every twelve
years, so don't waste this opportunity.
So don't waste this opportunity.
Do whatever you need
to hide your identity and gender.
I know you all.
I have selected each one of you.
No one else knows who you are.
But there may be people who get a thrill
from finding out who you are.
Similarly, there will be some of you who
might get a thrill
from finding out who others are.
Anonymity is power.
If you give away your identity,
you give away your power.
There may also be people who already
know you
or who have an axe to grind with you.
They may take this opportunity to harm
you.
Being anonymous is intoxicating.
It brings out the reckless side of
people.
So be careful now and the rest of your
life.
Always watch your backs.
Your masks are your temporary identity
but they also protect you.
Your power is that you are unknown.
If you are in danger here, blow your
whistle.
But there is also a ceremony to
celebrate life and death.
So, we have dances, parties and plays.
They can happen anytime. There is no
fixed time.
If you decide to go out of our boundary
before we are finished,
you can't come back, now or ever.
I know some of you will break the rules.
If you do, you will be unmasked
and your identity will be known by all.
You will be haunted for the rest of
your lives.
If you do something really grave,
we will make you disappear
and no one will ever know because no
one knows you're here.
The guards and I will be watching over
you.
This man was caught rummaging through
another's belongings.
We shall decide what we will do with him
before No Moon.
But for now, we will have to lock him up
because he may know some of your
identities.
Announcing the first act! Come everyone!
[Correct subtitle text needed - appears to be garbled]
Commencing immediately on the main stage!
Listen to me
The death that you fear most has come.
Fear not death, but be afraid of birth.
You are in the bardo.
You are on the border of death and birth.
You are alone here.
If you hear me,
it's your mind hearing it.
Even though you are dead, your mind's
ear will hear me talking to you
ear will hear me talking to you.
Your eyes, ears, tongue, nose and body
have left you.
You will also hear your relatives crying.
Let go of them.
They don't know how to let go of you.
Your soul will be in the Bardo realm
It's uncertain how long you will linger
here.
Listen,
In the presence of the Lord of Death
in the court of the Netherworld,
you will be judged.
Today you will be judged.
Have you deprived anyone of life?
Have you taken things that are not given?
Have you raped body or mind of others?
And now the Snake will see with his dice.
Oh you, have you seduced your mother?
Have you chewed and swallowed your
daughter?
Have you raped your father?
And now the pig will look at his mirror
and see everything.
Do not hide your negative actions, you
must confess.
Yes, you are hiding something!
Yes, you have let a whole family suffer
on earth.
Pig can see it.
What did you do?
You had better confess before we find
out,
or else you will also be judged as a
liar,
and the repercussions will be graver yet.
“Wait!”
Says the White Goddess
There must be one thing he has done
right.
Now, Monkey will weigh his deeds.
The White Goddess urges the dead man to
confess:
'You must confess. It's all your mind,
you are confessing to your own mind.'
'He must have done at least a few good
things in his past lives.'
Nothing is predestined.
Nothing is free will.
There are no accidents.
Come OH.
Okay... but you go first.
Plant rice, rice will grow.
Plant barley, barley will grow.
Plant negative actions,
suffering will grow.
Is that all you could find?
Me, I had to go into the mask room.
You look so funny!
What is it? Why aren't you saying
anything?
Hey, who are you?
I asked who are you.
Who are you?
Answer me
What are you doing?
Let me go!
I said let me go!
Oh, Noble one. Fear not death,
for you are already dead.
This evening, someone was killed.
Be careful, the killer is among us,
we may not know who did this.
Even if we know we are bound by our oath
never to reveal identities.
But I want to tell the killer
that your own conscience will haunt you
forever.
For now, we will offer him the finest
funeral of our custom.
You won't have a shadow. Nor will you
have a footprint.
You may have made your way back to your
home, but no one is speaking to you,
but no one is speaking to you,
because no one sees you.
Do not scream, for no one hears.
You have awoken from the dream of this
life.
You will soon slip into the dream of the
next life.
We hope it will be a shining one.
You have been stripped of the apparel of
this body.
Aim for a good one for the next life.
For now, you are naked,
this is not a moment to be wasted.
Being naked is precious.
Avoid looking back when you hear the
cries of your loved ones.
Be not in haste to choose the next
companions or home.
All what you see and hear, you see and
hear
because you looked and listened.
You are your own master.
You are your own architect.
You are your own ferryman.
You are the boat, you are the oars.
Do not be disheartened by the horizon of
the infinite ocean of life,
for the horizon is here and now.
24 YEARS LATER, YEAR OF THE FIRE MONKEY
Have you been here before?
Twelve years ago, is it?
Oh. You're an oldie
Do you remember the rules?
Hey, times have changed but the rules
are mostly the same.
We don't know you. You don't know us.
No one knows each other here,
and that's your power.
Your father or mother, could also be
here.
But, of course, you wouldn't know.
So, I suggest you don't go pinching
anyone's bottom.
Understand?
You have been dead for a long time.
Now you will forget your name.
Old friends and family mean nothing now.
You will be famished for different foods
and long for different nests.
You have been dead for a long time.
Now you will forget your name.
Old friends and family mean nothing now.
You will be famished for different foods
and long for different nests.
Agay.
What?
What's happening?
A tent caught on fire. Nothing to worry
about.
But Agay... listen to me.
Have you ever raped someone?
What?!
Who is this?!
Are you going crazy?
Crazy? I have been crazy for 24 years.
Get out!
I'll call the guards.
Go ahead.
Blow your horn.
I left a note in my home,
that if do not return in several days,
I have been murdered by you.
Wait...
Calm down
Tell me where she is?
You know the rules.
To hell with your rules!
Why do you want to know?
Wait...
Did you rape her?
I never knew a momentary incident would
affect my whole life.
Think twice before you show your face.
My life was finished a long time ago.
I have nothing to lose, I have no face.
Oh, now I know,
You also killed her husband too
didn't you?
I have been searching for her everywhere.
Tell me where she is.
Where is she?
She's dead.
She died giving birth to a daughter.
Are you saying...
She may be yours...
Maybe not.
Where is the girl?
How much do you make?
What if...
you didn't have to work here?
I mean... what if you didn't have to
work here?
What? Will you take care of me?
Wait for me.
(Hema Hema)
Writer and Director Writer and Director
Producer Pawo Choyning Dorji Sarah Chen
Executive producer Jeremy Thomas
Cinematography Jigme Tenzing